Finding Aid for Edwin S. George Reserve (Mich.) records, 1924-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Edwin S. George Reserve (Mich.) records 1924-2013, 1941-1995
Edwin S. George Reserve (Mich.)
4.58 MB
12 oversize folders
15 linear feet (in 16 boxes)
2013089 Bimu C459 2
Records of the Edwin S. George Reserve, Livingston County, Michigan, operated by the University of Michigan as a natural area for scientific study. Collection includes administrative records, history, publications, research, photographs, maps, and other records relating to Reserve activities.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was received from the Department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology (donor no. 10321 ) in May 2013.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The Edwins S. George records are open for research except for two folders of student academic records.
The Edwins S. George record group includes restricted material in the following categories:
Student Academic Records -- Boxes 16
The Edwin S. George Reserve is approximately 1,300 acres of land located in Livingston County and administered by the University of Michigan. The land, originally farms, was purchased in 1927 by Col. Edwin S. George, a Detroit businessman and philanthropist, for use as a game reserve. In 1930, Col. George donated the land to the University of Michigan to "further visual education in the natural sciences and for the purpose of preserving and demonstrating the native fauna and flora to the end that students interested in zoology, ornithology, botany, nature study and nature sketching, landscape studies, parks in a broad natural sense, or ecology, may here find material for observation and satisfy and develop the love for God's out-of-doors -- Nature" (Box 1, Board of Regents, 1930-1974, "Press Proof: The Regents Meeting, November Meeting 1931").
Under the terms of the gift agreement, Col. George and his heirs would be allowed to continue using the house and other buildings on the property and would retain control of 40 acres of the land, while the University agreed to provide a curator and assistants as needed to ensure the protection, care, and upkeep of the Reserve. The land would be made available to students and nature study groups of non-educational organizations, provided they abided by the rules outlined by the University. The original land donation has been augmented over the years, through other land gifts as well as purchases by the University and upon the death of Col. George, his family turned over the house and the reserved 40 acres to the University.
The Board of Regents assigned the Reserve to be administered as a unit of the University Museums, and it eventually became a division of the Museum of Zoology, administered by the director of the Museum under the immediate direction of the resident curator of the Reserve. An advisory committee, composed of representatives from interested departments within the College of Literature, Science, and the Arts and the School of Natural Resources and Environment, was also created to help with the supervision of the Reserve. As of 2013, the Reserve is administered by the Department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology. As stipulated by the gift agreement, the University provided a Curator for the Reserve. Past curators include Paul F. Hickie, Adolph Murie, Lawrence Camburn, Frederick Hamerstrom, Jr., and Irving J. Cantrall.
In 1950, the administration of the Reserve was reorganized and the reserve was overseen by an executive committee. The Chairman of the committee, J. Speed Rogers, was to act as director of the Reserve. Other directors include Theodore H. Hubbell, Nelson J. Hairston, Donald W. Tinkle, and William R. Dawson. During this time, there was also an Associate Director, a position that may have been the equivalent of Curator. This position was held most notably by Francis C. Evans, from 1959-1982, who made several notable contributions to Reserve research. He was succeeded by Ronald A. Nussbaum, who held the position until 2006. The current director, Earl Werner, will retire in December 2013.
In keeping with its mission, the Reserve has been the subject of numerous long and short-term studies on various plant and animal species. Dating back to 1941, when Col. George established a trust fund to be used to provide scholarships, the Edwin S. George Reserve Fellowship has assisted scholars in conducting research at the Reserve. The Evans Old Field, a 7.7 hectare abandoned field located inside the Reserve, has been a particularly prominent area of study and often features in publications. There is an impressive body of work featuring the Reserve, with an estimated 475 published studies including 81 dissertations and 31 Masters theses with some or all research conducted on the Reserve.
The Edwin S. George Reserve records document the history, administration, and research activities of the Reserve, which is owned and operated by the University of Michigan. The collection includes 15 linear feet of boxed material, as well as oversized photographs and maps and dates from 1929 to 2010. However, many of the dates listed in the collection, particularly dates for the research records, reflect the dates of the information in the record rather than the date the actual record was created, to better represent the research period. The records are arranged in seven series: Administrative Records, Publications and Papers, Research, Deer Herd, Photographs, Maps, and the Archived Website.
Subjects:
Botany--Michigan--Edwin S. George Reserve.; Edwin S. George Reserve (Mich.); Insects--Michigan.; Livingston County (Mich.); Natural history--Michigan--Edwin S. George Reserve.; University of Michigan. Department of Ecology and Evolutionary Biology.; University of Michigan. Museum of Zoology.; White-tailed deer--Michigan--Edwin S. George Reserve.; Wildlife management--Michigan.; Zoology--Michigan--Edwin S. George Reserve.
- Administrative Records
  The Administrative Records series (1.5 linear feet), 1930-2002, includes historical information and physical descriptions of the E.S. George Reserve, correspondence, meeting minutes, and information about the facilities and maintenance of the reserve.
  - Background
    - Board of Regents 1930 (copies)-1974 (Box 1)
    - Evans Old Field (EOF) History 1953-1996 (Box 1)
    - Gaige, F.M. Description -- ESGR 1938 (Box 1)
    - Hamerstrom Report on ESGR 1946 (Box 1)
    - History and Information 1942-1975 (Box 1)
    - Physical and Historical Information 1942-1971 (Box 1)
    - Press Clippings 1948-2002 (Box 1)
  - Property
    - Buck Hollow Core Log 1967 (Box 1)
    - General 1947-1997 (Box 1)
    - Oil and Gas Exploration 1953-1983 (Box 1)
    - Surveys 1970-1997 (Box 1)
  - Reserve Administration
    - Accounts 1946-1974 (Box 1)
    - Advisory Committee 1962-1989 (Box 1)
    - Annual Reports 1950-1955 (Box 1)
    - Bi-Monthly Reports 1949-1951 (Box 1)
    - Camburn, Larry 1949-1957 (Box 1)
    - Correspondence
      - Edwin S. George -- Will 1947-1952 (Box 1)
      - Evans, Francis C. 1960-1997, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - General 1952-1999 (Box 1)
      - Housing 1984-1995 (Box 1)
    - Executive Committee 1940-2000 (Box 1)
    - ESGR Committee 1968-1978 (Box 1)
    - General 1940-1956 (Box 1)
    - Housing 1956-1971 (Box 1)
    - Keys Issued 1951-1972 (Box 1)
    - Memos, Policies, and Forms 1947-1998 (Box 1)
    - Report to Staff Regarding Activity 1979 (Box 1)
    - Reserve Use
      - Electronic Defense Group 1961 (Box 1)
      - Infrared Physics Laboratory 1962-1967 (Box 1)
      - Requests for Use, 3 folders
        - Folders 1-2 1954-2003 (Box 1)
        - Folder 3 1954-2003 (Box 2)
    - Selection of New Director 1981-1984 (Box 2)
  - Facilities and Maintenance
    - Buildings 1951-1989 (Box 2)
    - Deer Exclosures 1949-1967 (Box 2)
    - ESGR Deer Fence 1987 (Box 2)
    - ESGR Fence 1962-1987 (Box 2)
    - ESGR Fence -- NSF Proposal Development 1984-1985 (Box 2)
    - ESGR Fence -- NSF Proposal Final 1979-1987 (Box 2)
    - Experimental Pond Facility 1987 (Box 2)
    - General 1947-1999 (Box 2)
    - Lab Marsh 1942-1947 (Box 2)
    - Properties Utility Survey -- Bowyer 1959 (Box 2)
    - South Gate Annex Building #15 1961-1962 (Box 2)
    - Support of Field Research Facilities Proposal undated (Box 2)
  - Scholarship Fund
    - Applications and Awards, 1947-1948 (Box 16)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2023 ]
    - Applications and Awards (Box 16)
      [SR RESTRICTED until July 1 2055 ]
    - Creation and Funding 1944-1996 (Box 2)
- Publications and Papers
  The Publications and Papers series (1.5 linear feet), 1932-2001, contains publications of studies and research conducted on the Reserve, as well as manuscripts for papers based on Reserve research. The series also contains student papers based on studies conducted at the Reserve for various courses.
  - Bibliographies circa 1954-2001 (Box 2)
  - Publications by Year
    - 1932-1940 (Box 2)
    - 1949-1953 (Box 2)
    - 1954-1959 (Box 2)
    - 1960-1961 (Box 2)
    - 1962-1964 (Box 2)
    - 1965-1969 (Box 2)
    - 1970-1974 (Box 2)
    - 1975-1979 (Box 2)
    - 1980-1985 (Box 2)
    - 1986-1991 (Box 3)
    - 1992-1993 (Box 3)
    - 1994-1997 (Box 3)
    - 1998-1999 (Box 3)
    - 2000-2001 (Box 3)
  - Adams, Scott "Two Alternative Master Plans for the Interpretation of George Reserve," 1971 (Box 3)
  - Collins, James P. and Henry M. Wilbur, "The Amphibians of the E.S. George Reserve, Michigan," undated (Box 3)
  - Dansereau, Pierre "The Plant Communities of the Edwin S. George Reserve," 1954 (Box 3)
  - Dumas, Philip C. "Comparison of the Hibernal and Vernal Avifauna of a Tamarack Bog and an Oak-Hickory Woodland in Southeastern Michigan," undated (Box 3)
  - Engelmann, Manfred D., Harold Heatwole, and J. Mester "Ecological Observations on Five Tree Holes in an Oak Hickory Forest in Southeastern Michigan," 1956 (Box 3)
  - Ecological Studies 1937-1947, 4 folders (Box 3)
  - Evans, Francis C. "Ecological Structure of the Insect Fauna of an Old-Field Community," undated (Box 3)
  - Evans, Francis C. "Ecology of Insect Fauna" Manuscript Notes undated (Box 3)
  - Evans, Francis C. and Urless N. Lanham, "The Insect Fauna of an Old Field Community," undated (Box 3)
  - Evans, Francis C. "Microcycles in an Old-Field Grassland Community in Southeastern Michigan," 1950-1951 (Box 3)
  - Evans, Francis C. and Richard G. Wiegart, Plant Productivity Manuscripts 1962-1963 (Box 3)
  - Evans, Francis C. "Succession After Disturbance," 1983 (Box 3)
  - Forestry 134 Ecology Studies 1937-1947, undated, 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Greene, Gordon, Thomas Hunt, Frederick Nelson, and Frederick Sleator, "The Analogy of a Frost Hollow to a Simple Net Radiometer," 1979 (Box 3)
  - Hileman, Douglas R. and Lynda Fox Lieto, "The Effects of the leaf miner Coptodisca kalmiella (Lepidoptera: Heliozelidae) on the bog shrub Chamaedaphne calyculata (Ericaceae)," 1980 (Box 3)
  - Kormondy, Edward J. "The Aquatic Arthropoda and Mollusca of Two Marshes on the George Reserve, Michigan," 1951-1953 (Box 3)
  - Meyer, Rudolph J. and Marvin B. Pittman, "The Migration of Black Oak from a Wood Lot into an Old Abandoned Field on Edwin S. George Reserve," 1957 (Box 3)
  - Miller, Lee D. Botany 572, "Changes in the Plant Communities in George Reserve as Determined from Aerial Photographs Taken Between 1936 and the Present," 1965 (Box 3)
  - Nelson, Mark L. "A Key for the Cytological Determination of Orthopteran Foods," 1973 (Box 3)
  - Proshek, Karl and Joseph Mendel, "The Effect of Deer Browse on the North-East Area of the Edwin S. George Reserve," undated (Box 3)
  - Riggs, Dixon L. "Progress Report in Mammalian Ecology," 1951-1952 (Box 3)
- Research
  The Research series (8.25 linear feet), 1939-1997, is the largest component of the collection and documents the research activities of the Reserve. The series is organized into subseries based on research areas, which include the Bee Study, Flowers, General, Insects, Plants, Projects, and Weather Records. The Bee Study includes data from 1948 to 1995 with particular emphasis on the years 1972 and 1973. The records, gathered primarily on Evans Old Field, include information on various species of bees and aspects such as phenology, plant visitation, and flight periods. This content is parallel to that of the Flowers series, which covers a similar time period and has information on flower phenology, bee visitation, flowering periods, and other information for a variety of plant species. The General series includes data on various animal and plant life on the Reserve that is not extensive enough to form its own series but still gives valuable information. The plant data contains information from a fifty year study conducted by Francis C. Evans on successional change on Evans Old Field. This data has also been captured in a database and these digital files have been included online. The Projects series is more administrative in nature and includes information on researchers, their projects, and research proposals involving the Reserve. The final subseries, Weather Records, includes daily and monthly weather records between 1951 and 1978, as well as information on the Reserve's Meteorology program.
  - Bee Study
    - Abundance 1949-1996 (Box 3)
    - Assessment of Importance 1949-1990 (Box 3)
    - Bee Biology 1949-1986 (Box 3)
    - Bee Data Sorted by Plant Species (Rachel Simpson) 1996 (Box 4)
    - Bee Flower Interactions
      - "Bee-Flower Interactions on an Old Field in Southeastern Michigan," Francis C. Evans 1986 (Box 4)
      - NA Prairie Conference 1984 (Box 4)
      - Notes 1974 (Box 4)
      - Notes (Green, Thomas G.) 1971-1972 (Box 4)
      - Presentation at Cary Arboretum 1986 (Box 4)
      - "Principal"/"Supplemental" Herbs and "Major" Bee Species 1949-1988 (Box 4)
      - Species Interactions 1972-1984 (Box 4)
    - Bee-Flower Study Correspondence 1958-1994 (Box 4)
    - Bee-Flower Study Days and Times of Collection/Observation 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Bee Phenology 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Bee Records -- ESGR 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - Bee Sociality 1949-1995 (Box 4)
    - Bee Visitation 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Bee Visitation (By Bee) 1949-1978 (Box 4)
    - Bee Visitation (By Flower) 1949-1978 (Box 4)
    - Complete List of Bees Collected 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Duration of Flight Periods 1949-1986 (Box 4)
    - Evans Old Field Bees
      - Colletidae, Andrenidae, and Halictidae 1949-1987 (Box 4)
      - Megachilidae 1949-1986 (Box 4)
      - Species and Study Records 1949-1995 (Box 4)
    - Field Records
      - (reconstructed) 1972 (Box 4)
      - 1973, 2 folders (Box 4)
      - 1974-1977 (Box 4)
      - 1978-1986 (Box 4)
      - 1987-1995 (Box 4)
    - Flight Period Analysis 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Flight Period Data 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Flight Period Patterns 1986-1989 (Box 4)
    - Flower Species Visited 1949-1990 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation 1949-1990 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation by Males 1949-1987 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation -- Herbs 1949-1990 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation Records 1988-1990 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation -- Shrubs 1949-1989 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation Statistics -- Bee Species 1949-1990 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation Statistics -- Resource Type 1949-1990 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation to Principal Resources, Herbs and Shrubs 1949-1990 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation to "Subsidiary" Resources (Herbs and Shrubs) 1949-1990 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visitation to Supplemental Resources 1949-1989 (Box 4)
    - Flower Visits by Importance 1949-1991 (Box 4)
    - "Frequent Visitors" Species 1949-1988 (Box 4)
    - Frequent Visitors to Flower Resources of 1972-1973, 1949-1986 (Box 4)
    - Keys and Codes for Study Data circa 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Late Season Activity undated (Box 4)
    - Limited Visitation 1949-1987 (Box 4)
    - Lists 1949-1979 (Box 4)
    - Miscellaneous Data 1972-1977 (Box 4)
    - Monarda Bee Relations 1972-1982 (Box 4)
    - Monarda Pollen Information 1948-1987 (Box 4)
    - "No-Flower" Records 1949-1990 (Box 4)
    - Occurrence -- Earliest/Latest, arranged taxonomically 1949-1990 (Box 4)
    - Occurrence of Species 1949-1989 (Box 4)
    - Pollen Collecting 1949-1986 (Box 4)
    - Pollen Loads Analysis, Humes and Duffield 1972-1976 (Box 4)
    - Polytropy and Oligotropy 1949-1995 (Box 4)
    - Records -- Non-Evans Old Field Sites 1949-1987 (Box 4)
    - Records of Occurrence 1949-1995 (Box 5)
    - Records of Occurrence and Flower Visitation 1982-1994 (Box 5)
    - Records of Occurrence -- Computer Printouts 1994 (Box 5)
    - Seasonal Distribution 1949-1986 (Box 5)
    - Seasonality of Occurrence 1949-1989 (Box 5)
    - SEM Photos of Bees by P. Dayanandan 1982 (Box 5)
    - Species
      - Andrena 1949-1989 (Box 5)
      - Apis Mellifora 1949-1991 (Box 5)
      - Bombus 1957-1994 (Box 5)
      - Halictidae (Eickwort) 1987 (Box 5)
      - Hylaeus, Colletes 1958-1986 (Box 5)
      - Megachile and Coelioxys 1983 (Box 5)
      - Melissodes 1957-1977 (Box 5)
      - Nomada 1957-1984 (Box 5)
    - Steinert, James -- Biology 990, Fall 1977 (Box 5)
    - Weather Information for Growing Seasons 1972-1973 (Box 5)
    - Weekly Changes in Species Visiting Flowers 1972-1973 (Box 5)
  - Bee Study
    - Bee-Flower Study -- Computer Data Printouts (Box 15)
      - All Locations and Evans Old Field 1949-1972 (Box 15)
      - Evans Old Field 1973 (Box 15)
      - Evans Old Field 1972 All Locations 1948-1971 and Non-Evans Old Field 1972, 1948-1972 (Box 15)
      - Evans Old Field -- Combined Bee Record 1972-1973 (Box 15)
      - Evans Old Field -- Flight Period and Flowering Period 1972 (Box 15)
    - Bee Occurrence 1949-1981 (Box 15)
    - Bee Visitation 1972-1973 (Box 15)
  - Flowers
    - Allocation 1948-1991 (Box 5)
    - Annual/Biennial vs. Perennial 1949-1987 (Box 5)
    - Assessment of Estimated Overlaps of Flowering Periods 1949-1981 (Box 5)
    - Availability of Floral Resources 1949-1988 (Box 5)
    - Bee Visitation 1949-1990 (Box 5)
    - Bee Visitation 1972-1973 (Box 5)
    - Bee Visitation to Selected Species 1949-1984 (Box 5)
    - Bee Visit Records 1974-1990 (Box 5)
    - Biological Characteristics 1949-1987 (Box 5)
    - Blooming Season 1972-1973 (Box 5)
    - Degree of Visitation (Polyphily vs. Oligophily) 1949-1990 (Box 5)
    - Dominants 1989 (Box 5)
    - Effects of Deer Grazing 1949-1986 (Box 5)
    - Flowering Periods 1948-1991 (Box 5)
    - Flowering Season 1949-1991 (Box 5)
    - Flower Phenology 1973-1979 (Box 5)
    - General Statistics and Notes on Bee Visitation 1949-1990 (Box 5)
    - Herbs/Shrubs 1948-1991 (Box 5)
    - Introduced vs. Native 1949-1987 (Box 5)
    - Miscellaneous Data 1972-1973 (Box 5)
    - Notes on Evans Old Field Flowers Attracting Specialist Bees undated (Box 5)
    - Notes -- Significant Resources 1949-1984 (Box 5)
    - Pollen undated (Box 5)
    - Principal, Seasonal, Subsidiary Resources 1949-1991 (Box 5)
    - Records of Flower Visitation by Bees and Other Insects 1948-1992, 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Relative Abundance 1947-1990 (Box 5)
    - Relative Importance 1949-1991 (Box 5)
    - Species Recorded in Bloom 1948-1992 (Box 5)
    - Success of Species 1949-1990 (Box 5)
  - General
    - Arachnids 1957-1971 (Box 5)
    - Birds and Mammals
      - Banding and Collecting Permits and Reports 1941-1948 (Box 5)
      - Bird Sightings 1941-1948 (Box 5)
      - Coyote 1942 (Box 6)
      - Evans Old Field Mammals circa 1954 (Box 6)
      - ESGR Mammals 1948-1949 (Box 6)
      - Fox 1942-1956 (Box 6)
      - Goose Relocation Program 1974-1995 (Box 6)
      - Ground Squirrels
        - 1949 (Box 6)
        - 1950 (Box 6)
        - 1951 (Box 6)
        - 1952 (Box 6)
        - 1953 (Box 6)
        - 1954 (Box 6)
        - 1955 (Box 6)
        - Citellus -- Dr. Cresbo 1955 (Box 6)
      - Mammal Trapping Records 1948-1954, 2 folders (Box 6)
      - Mink 1942 (Box 6)
      - Muskrat 1941 (Box 6)
      - Nesting Records 1941 (Box 6)
      - Old Field Study Vertebrate Notes 1880-1981 (Box 6)
      - Raccoon 1942 (Box 6)
      - Small Mammal Trapping -- Evans Old Field 1969 (Box 6)
      - Swale Trapping 1950-1954 (Box 6)
      - Vertebrate Lists 1939-1991 (Box 6)
    - Collembola Identifications 1957 (Box 6)
    - Diplopoda 1969-1972 (Box 6)
    - ESGR Fungi and Lichens 1967-1975 (Box 6)
    - Evans Old Field Biota 1954-1992 (Box 6)
    - Evans Old Field Invertebrate Collections 1948-1956 (Box 6)
    - Field Notes 1944-1954 (Box 6)
    - Mollusca 1939-1972 (Box 6)
    - Old Field Study Phenology Notes
      - July 16-November, 1948-1997 (Box 6)
      - June-July 15, 1949-1997 (Box 6)
      - March-May, 1949-1997 (Box 6)
    - Soil
      - Department of Geography Soil Survey by O.H. Lovejoy 1940 (Box 6)
      - Soil Data and Notes 1949-1983 (Box 6)
      - Soil Divisions -- Veatch 1953-1999 (Box 6)
    - Worms
      - Aggregation in the Earthworm 1967 (Box 6)
      - Annelida 1954 (Box 6)
      - Earthworms 1960-1962 (Box 6)
      - Field Notes and Sample Code 1960 (Box 6)
      - Graduate Ecology Lab Report -- Worm Aggregation, Fall 1961 (Box 6)
      - Notes 1961-1962 (Box 6)
      - Oligochaetes 1960 (Box 6)
      - Worm Study -- Gill undated (Box 6)
  - Insects
    - Cage Collections
      - Cage Collections 1957 (Box 6)
      - Frequency Analysis of Species in Cage Samples 1957 (Box 6)
      - Records of Collection at "Stations," 1957 (Box 6)
      - "Species-Area" Curve 1957 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence 1958-1959 (Box 6)
    - Densities 1958-1964 (Box 6)
    - Food Habits 1959-1967 (Box 6)
    - Frame Quadrat Analysis of "Other" Insects -- Numbers and Densities 1958 (Box 6)
    - Frequency 1958-1959 (Box 6)
    - Malaise Trap 1963-1964 (Box 6)
    - Methodology 1930-1967 (Box 6)
    - Plant Notes 1961-1975 (Box 6)
    - Seasonal Succession 1959-1964 (Box 6)
    - Seasonal Succession -- Miscellaneous Notes on Seasonal Occurrence 1949-1957 (Box 6)
    - Seasonal Succession -- Slide Materials, Ecological Society of America, Boulder, CO 1964 (Box 6)
    - Species Lists
      - "Characteristics" Species Lists 1959-1964 (Box 6)
      - Evans Old Field Insects -- Lists of Species 1966 (Box 6)
      - Evans Old Field Insects -- List of Species Annotated for Community Layer and Food Habits 1961-1983 (Box 6)
      - Insects Species Lists 1943-1970 (Box 7)
      - Lists of Species 1959-1990 (Box 7)
    - Sweep Samples
      - Sweep Samples 1958 (Box 7)
      - Sweep Samples April -- May, 1959 (Box 7)
      - Sweep Samples June -- July, 1959 (Box 7)
      - Sweep Samples Aug -- Sept 1959 (Box 7)
      - R2, F20, and F14 undated (Box 7)
      - F14 1961 (Box 7)
      - Analysis 1958 (Box 7)
      - Analysis 1959 (Box 7)
      - Frequency of Common Species 1961 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous undated (Box 7)
      - Weights and Biomass 1958 (Box 7)
      - Weights and Biomass 1957-1958 (Box 7)
    - Synoptic Collection (Species Code Lists) 1957-1960 (Box 7)
    - Total Fauna Partitioning-Partitioning of Fauna Notes and Manuscript undated (Box 7)
    - Total Fauna Partitioning -- Species List with Assignments to Weight, Density, Biomass, and Food Habits Categories undated (Box 7)
    - Various Orders
      - Ants -- Evans Old Field 1965-1985 (Box 7)
      - Bombyliidae 1961-1964 (Box 7)
      - Braconidae undated (Box 7)
      - Coleophera -- Tom Green Notes 1971-1972 (Box 7)
      - Coleoptera circa 1953-1958 (Box 7)
      - Diptera 1953-1964 (Box 7)
      - Homoptera Data and Correspondence 1964-1973 (Box 7)
      - Homoptera -- Murdoch, Evans, and Peterson Data 1964-1967 (Box 7)
      - Hymenoptera 1951-1960 (Box 7)
      - Lepidoptera 1950-1974 (Box 7)
      - Lepidoptera Coleophera 1969-1971 (Box 7)
      - Lepidoptera -- "The Microlepidoptera of Livingston County, Michigan," 1953 (Box 7)
      - Miscellaneous 1951-1959 (Box 7)
      - Odonata 1949-1957 (Box 7)